# Ekene D. Onoh

Fontana, CA • (909) 301-1894 • ekene.onoh123@gmail.com • ekeneonoh456.github.io

#### PROFESSIONAL STATEMENT

As organizations around the globe become more dependent on technology, the need for technically skilled
individuals who can aid these companies becomes more blatant. While I possess programming, networking,
analytical, and problem-solving skills along with experience in cybersecurity and software engineering, my
ability to lead, remain optimistic, learn fast, and cooperate with others allows me to be a morale boost and a
solid contributor to any team in the IT industry.

# CERTIFICATIONS

- CompTIA Security+ CE
  - o Credential ID: VNKGMQEV17K6V5GZ
- CompTIA Network+ CE
  - o Credential ID: CD4CZS0YN2RE1Y35
- Google Cybersecurity
  - o Credential ID: 8WTT5BE69DNC

# **EXPERIENCE**

- IT Helpdesk Support (2024)
  - Managed and provided support using Windows Server 2016 and Active Directory as a domain controller.
  - Helped with user account management by assisting with resetting passwords, delegating controls, locking, unlocking, enabling, and disabling accounts.
  - Configured account expirations and renewals.
  - Mapped shared network drives and folders.
  - Provided remote support using RSAT Tools, Windows Remote Assistance, Spiceworks ticketing system, and Zoho RDP Tools.
  - Used PDQ Inventory and PDQ Deploy to install software packages on domain computers.
- Cyber Security Researcher (2023)

# **Apollo Information Systems**

- Internship working with AIS where I was tasked with researching modern hacking tools, collecting data about companies that have been attacked, and assisting companies with improving web security.
- Software Engineer (2022)

# **Tata Consultancy Services**

- Internship with TCS where our team developed a full stack web application that was a live chat program for customer support.
- I was specifically tasked with building and making the messaging component functional within the application.
- Network Administrator (2024)
  - Project where I created VMs to simulate network environments.
  - Created Active Directory Domain where I created and connected users, security groups, computers, printers, and permission configurations..
  - Coded PowerShell scripts to automate various tasks within Active Directory.
- Web & App Development (2023-2024)

# **Built Portfolio Website**

- o ekeneonoh456.github.io
- Created a website that holds my professional portfolio and experience using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Google Apps Script. It is currently being hosted using Github Pages.

#### **Bowie State University Shuttle App**

- A part of a team that built an app for our school's shuttle service.
- Hackathons & Competitions (2022-Present)
  - NCAE Cyber Games Spring 2022, NCCDC Hivestorm Fall 2022, National Cyber League (NCL), AWS HBCU 2022 Business Case Competition, MorganHacks 2023, UMD BitCamp 2023
- Math Tutor and Teacher Assistant (2020-2023)

### **Bowie State University**

- Worked as a math tutor and teacher assistant assisting and teaching students in a wide range of college math courses.
- Treasurer (2021-2023)

# BSU Disciples, BSU Circle K International, and BSU Honors Student Organization

 Managing the budgets and financial records for multiple organizations. BSU Disciples is a Bible study/support group, BSU Circle K International is a community service organization, and BSU Honors Student Organization is the school's Honors Program.

# **TECHNICAL & SOFT SKILLS**

- Programming Languages: Python, JavaScript, Java, C, C++, PowerShell Script, HTML, CSS, VHDL
- Command Line: Linux, Unix, PowerShell, SSH
- Web & App Development: React Native, React.js, Spring Boot, Postman, RabbitMQ, Maven, Angular, PHP, Git & GitHub, Google Apps Script
- Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MariaDB, Oracle, CockroachDB
- Cloud: AWS, Cloud Networking
- Security: SIEM Tools, Splunk, Risk Assessment, Threat Detection, Security Intelligence & Research, Threat & Vulnerability Management, Network & Web Security, Shodan, Firewalls, Security Groups & Permissions
- Networking & IT: System Configuration, Software Defined Networking, Local Area Networks, Switches, Routers, Network Management Systems, DNS, DHCP, TCP/UDP, VPN, Active Directory, VMs, Windows Server 2016, User Account Creation, Adding Computers to Domains, User Account Management, RSAT Tools, Group Policy Management, Lock/Unlock Accounts, Enable/Disable Accounts, Account Expiration & Renewal, Enable/Disable Domain Computers, Shared Drives & Folders, Mapping Network Drives, Remote Desktop Support, Remote Registry, Windows Remote Assistance, PDQ Deploy & Software Packages, PDQ Inventory, Adding Printers to Domains, Ticketing Systems, Spiceworks, Zoho RDP Tools, Microsoft Account Lockout & Management Tools, Domain Delegation Controls, Resetting Passwords
- Troubleshooting: Networks, Operating Systems, Windows, Microsoft Applications, macOS, Linux
- **Soft Skills:** Teamwork, Optimistic, Tutoring, Analytical, Problem Solving, Fast Learner, Open-minded, Customer Service & Support, Technical Support, Communication, Morale Boosting

#### **EDUCATION**

- Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, Bowie State University, Bowie, MD
- Etiwanda High School, Rancho Cucamonga, CA

# **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Bowie State University Honors Program
- Dean's List at Bowie State University (3.8 GPA)
- National Society of Leadership and Success Member (NSLS)